## Baibhabi Goswami

Darmstadt, Germany | +353-899469929 | baibhabi.goswami@ucdconnect.ie |

| linkedin.com/in/baibhabi-goswami/ | baibhabigoswami.github.io |

### **Profile**

Finance graduate with 7 years' experience in accounting, auditing, financial reporting, and tax planning. Entrepreneurial spirit led to the founding of a financial consulting firm. Strong analytical skills with excellent interpersonal and communication skills, developed while working with culturally diverse teams. Demonstrates a commitment to driving financial performance alongside positive environmental and social impact.

### Education

MSc. in Sustainable Finance (Grade 1:1)	2023 – 2024
UCD Michael Smurfit Graduate Business School, Dublin, Ireland	
Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (ACCA-part qualified)	2022-
Completed practical training and 6 out of 13 modules.	
Integrated Professional Competence Exam (CA-Inter)	2016 - 2020
Institute of Chartered Accountants of India, India	
Master's in Commerce (Grade 1:1)	2018 - 2020
Indira Gandhi National Open University, India	
Post-Graduate Diploma in International Business Operations (Grade 1:1)	2018 - 2020
Indira Gandhi National Open University, India	
Bachelor's in Commerce (Grade 1:1, with distinction)	2013 - 2016
Ravenshaw University, Cuttack, India	

# **Career Experience**

Research Assistant, UCD, Dublin, Ireland

Nov 2023 – July 2024

- Conducted comprehensive literature reviews to underpin current research projects.
- Designed and employed suitable econometric tests.
- Has been responsible for drafting the write up of 3 academic papers.

Article Assistant, Raj Aniruddh & Associates, New Delhi, India

Nov 2019 - Oct 2020

- Led the organisation-wide annual balance sheets and income statements finalisation process and corporate reporting, coordinating with cross-functional teams to enhance efficiency and accuracy.
- Enhanced the direct tax services team's performance, successfully implementing strategies that led to a reduction of up to 15% in tax liabilities for select clients while maintaining full compliance.
- Advocated for the adoption of virtual financial services during the COVID-19 period, contributing to the sustenance of client trust and achieving a 7% increase in monthly turnover.

Article Assistant, Arun Malhotra & Associates, New Delhi, India

Nov 2016 - Nov 2019

- Directed a variety of audit engagements, including statutory, tax, stock, and internal audits, and proactively identified errors, preventing a client from incurring a potential fine of INR 2 million once.
- Was integral to a special fraud investigation unit, traced approx. INR 30 million in misappropriated funds, demonstrating sharp analytical skills and a commitment to financial integrity.

- Maintained general ledger integrity, achieving flawless financial records, and reducing cash flow statement reconciliation errors by 40%, thereby enhancing decision-making reliability and adherence to fiscal compliance.
- Streamlined the account closure and finalisation process, cutting down the cycle time by up to 20%, expediting the year-end closing activities, and supporting timely and accurate financial reporting.

# **Working Papers**

- Goswami B., Dutta S. <u>Fiscal Performance & Economic Growth: A cross-state empirical analysis</u> between Tripura and Developed States of India. (2023).
- Goswami B., Gupta N. Greening the Grid: Evaluating renewable energy's contribution to lowering India's carbon intensity and climate commitments. (2023).
- Goswami B., Bredin D., Muckley C. Do Global Carbon Prices signal high Policy Credibility? (2024).
- *Masters' Dissertation:* 18 Years of Market-Based Climate Action: Efficacy of the EU ETS. (2024). Supervisor: Dr. Kevin (Yong Kyu) Gam.

#### **Additional Skills**

- Languages: English (proficient), Bengali (native), Hindi (proficient), Oriya (conversant).
- Programming Language: Julia; MATLAB; Python.
- IT Skills: STATA(beginner); LaTeX; SQL; Advanced user of Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint).
- Certification: Bloomberg; Tally ERP9.

#### **Other Information**

- Awards: Kulapati K.M. Munshi Award in Mathematics, Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan (2011); Certificate of Commendation, Shikhan Bharati (2011); Subramaniam Character Certificate, BTVM (2008).
- Achievements: Second rank, Bachelor's in Commerce, Ravenshaw University (2016); AISSCE State topper (2013); Perfect CGPA (10.0/10.0) in AISSE (2011).
- Volunteer: Ray's Foundation, Odisha (2016-2023).
- Interest: Regional theatre and recitation; recipient of Biswajt Das Memorial Award (2007).